Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications Print Advertisements, 1991-2005 RL.10999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications print advertisements
1991-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.10999
6 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Brouillard Communications, a division of JWT, was established in 1973 and specialized in business-to-business advertising and corporate communications. Brouillard closed in 2009. Collection spans the years 1995-2005 and contains primarily proofs of print advertising campaigns, along with some tear sheets and printouts of PDF files. Some brochures, printed materials and direct mailing items are also present in the collection. Companies represented include American Gas Association, American Physical Therapy Association, Barclays, Bell Atlantic, CITCO, Dassault, Dow Jones, Johns Manville, Maserati, Morgan Stanley and United Technologies. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found within the following Hartman Center collections:
Arthur Einstein Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company Domestic Advertisements
John F. Hogan Papers
Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements
Collection Overview
Collection spans the years 1995-2005 and contains primarily proofs of print advertising campaigns, along with some tear sheets and printouts of PDF files. Some brochures, printed materials and direct mailing items are also present in the collection. Companies represented include American Gas Association, American Physical Therapy Association, Barclays, Bell Atlantic, CITCO, Dassault, Dow Jones, Johns Manville, Maserati, Morgan Stanley and United Technologies. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications. Print Advertisements were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2004-2006
Advertising; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Institutional advertising; Institutional advertising -- United States; Morgan Stanley & Co; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Brouillard Communications, Inc.; Bell Atlantic Corporation; J. Walter Thompson Company
- Brouillard print advertisements, 1991-2004 and undated; 1
  - Adweek (UK), Best Spots mailer and application, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Atlantic Mutual Insurance, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Bear Stearns, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Big Bear grocery stores, circa 2002 (Box 1)
  - Dassault Falcon airplanes (English and Spanish), 2002-2004 (Box 1)
  - Greenpoint Bank, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Kimberly-Clark, press kit label, 2004 (Box 1)
  - LAIcompass.com, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Financial Group, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Maserati, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Prebone Yamane, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
  - Salvation Army, annual reports, 1997-2003 (Box 1)
  - Security Capital, circa 1997 (Box 1)
  - America's Community Bankers, circa 1996 (Box 2)
  - American Gas Association, 1998-1999; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - American Physical Therapy Association, 1996-1999; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - American Re (American Reinsurance, Zurich Re), 1996-1997 and undated; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - American Society of Travel Agents (ASTA), 1997 (Box 2)
  - Astoria Federal Savings (English, Spanish, Greek, Russian), 1999-2002; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Atlantic Mutual Insurance, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Barclay's Capital, 1998-1999; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Bell Atlantic (English and Spanish), 1996-1999 (Box 2)
  - Brouillard Communications, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Chicago Board Brokerage/Market Power, 1998 (Box 2)
  - CIBC, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
  - CITCO Group (English, German and Spanish), 1997-1999; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Dassault Falcon airplanes, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Dow Jones, 1997-1999; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - First Union, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Fresh Australian Range Lamb, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Greenpoint Bank, 1995-1998 (Box 2)
  - Instinet (UK), 1999; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Johns Manville, 1997-1998; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Maserati, 2002 and undated (Box 3)
  - Morgan Stanley Dean Witter (English, German, Japanese, Italian), 1996-1999; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - New York Mercantile Exchange, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Praxair, 1997; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Prologis, 1998 (Box 3)
  - UNC Hospitals, 1999 (Box 3)
  - United States Tobacco Company, 1997-1998; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - United Technologies (English, Chinese), 1996-1999; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - UST, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - Wagner Stott Bear Specialists, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Wheat First Securities, 1999 (Box 3)
  - American Gas Association, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - American Re (American Reinsurance, Zurich Re), 1997-1998 and undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - American Society of Travel Agents (ASTA), 1997 (Box 4)
  - Bell Atlantic, 1997-1999; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - CIBC, 1997-2002; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Dassault Falcon airplanes, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Dow Jones (English, German, French), 1997-1998; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Dynergy, 1998 (Box 4)
  - First Union, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Johns Manville, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Maserati, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Morgan Stanley Dean Witter, 1997-1999; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Praxair, 1997; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Tenneco, 1996 (Box 5)
  - United States Tobacco Company, 1997-1998; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - United Technologies (English, Chinese), 1996-1999; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - UST, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Visa, 1997; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - York, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - American Physical Therapy Association, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - American Re (American Reinsurance, Zurich Re), 1997 (Box 6)
  - Bell Atlantic (English and Spanish), 1997 (Box 6)
  - CIBC, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Dow Jones, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Johns Manville, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Morgan Stanley Dean Witter, 1997-1999 (Box 6)
  - United Technologies, 1997-1999 (Box 6)